Contact

jdlewinski@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jacoblewinski (LinkedIn)

Top Skills
ASP.NET Core
JavaScript
SQL

Jacob Lewinski

Senior Software Engineer

Huntsville, Alabama, United States

Summary

I am an experienced software developer specialized in building web applications that enhance the lives of the others. I have a strong foundation with years of experience using ASP.NET Core MVC with vanilla JS. Recently, I have helped multiple projects grow by modernizing the tech stack to include a frontend framework like Svelte and React. I have enjoyed experimenting with different technologies and the differences in performance and developer experience.

When I'm not working or learning, I am a loving husband and father. Lately I have been cherishing the time I get to play with my one-year-old daughter and going on dates with my amazing wife.

Experience

Alliance Technical Group
2 years 1 month
Senior Software Developer
September 2024 - Present (1 year)

Software Developer II

August 2023 - September 2024 (1 year 2 months)

Powerserve

Software Engineer

September 2021 - July 2023 (1 year 11 months)

Developing and maintaining applications for various clients. Most applications are ASP.NET MVC applications. Other applications include ASP.NET CORE MVC, Console Applications, and mobile applications.

Developing tables, views, and stored procedures in SQL database for applications to interface with.

Torch Technologies, Inc.
Software Engineer
April 2020 - September 2021 (1 year 6 months)
Huntsville, Alabama, United States

Full Stack development using .NET products. Developed many internal WPF applications as well as working on a larger WPF application as well as a new ASP.NET Core MVC application.

Robins Air Force Base Electronics Engineer June 2019 - April 2020 (11 months)

Developing and maintaining applications (.NET) to enable testing and development of embedded systems as well as some applications for general project management.

Additionally develop and maintain the embedded systems (C++).

Auburn University
Campus Web Solutions Full Stack Developer
January 2017 - June 2019 (2 years 6 months)
Auburn, Alabama

Full stack web development using mainly Visual Studio and Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio. Here I learned and developed with C#, SQL, JS, MVC, Knockout.js, etc. I worked with a team of fellow COOP students to develop web applications. Specific projects have been listed bellow. For my last year I was the leader of our team as a mentor.

Best Buy
Sales Associate
June 2016 - August 2016 (3 months)
Mayfield Heights, Oh

Provide customers with a complete solution through selling computer products and services.

Sandbox Computers for Kids, Inc. Software Developer and Instructor June 2015 - October 2015 (5 months) Thousand Oaks, California

Responsibilities include, but are not limited to, designing applications for teaching material and administrative purposes, teaching students K-12,

collaborating on curriculum content development, developing lesson plans, reviewing assignments, assigning and mentoring students on projects, participating in faculty development, teaching in one of our studios, traveling to schools / after-schools to conduct classes, and supporting promotional and outreach activities.

Conejo Teen Organization
Website Designer / Tutor
June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months)
Westlake Village, Ca

Creating and designing a website that conveys the message of the organization in a way that is simple to navigate.

Helping 6-12 graders with homework, projects, and studying for tests. Giving business advice and helping the company shape and grow. Helping organize and run events.

Additional responsibilities.

Staples

Technology Associate September 2014 - January 2015 (5 months)

Westlake Vilage, California

Providing technical assistance, selling technology (computers, tablets, smart phones, wireless hot spots, routers, etc.), and working in other departments as needed.

Safeway

Combo Clerk

June 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 4 months)

Checking, bagging, making sure the store ran smoothly, providing excellent customer service, and working in other departments as needed.

Education

Auburn University

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering (2016 - May 2019)

Moorpark College

Pre-Engineering · (2014 - 2015)

Agoura High School

High School, General Studies · (2010 - 2014)